<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Owen Smith</title>
        <link>https://owensmith.page/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Owen Smith</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owensmith.page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>This was supposed to be just a weekend project...</title>
        <link>https://owensmith.page/p/this-was-supposed-to-be-just-a-weekend-project/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://owensmith.page/p/this-was-supposed-to-be-just-a-weekend-project/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://owensmith.page/p/this-was-supposed-to-be-just-a-weekend-project/reddit.PNG" alt="Featured image of post This was supposed to be just a weekend project..." /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-simple-side-project&#34;&gt;A simple side project&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/owenps/Castlemates&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Castlemates&lt;/a&gt; was supposed to be just a weekend project. I had no idea that the repository would hit over 230 unique vistors and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/chess/comments/ojiy7p/top_25_rated_games_ending_in_a_checkmate_by&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;over 650 upvotes on Reddit&lt;/a&gt; in just over a day. I had an idea to build a python script which scrapes .pgn (portable game notation) files for chess games which end in a checkmate by castling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty simple idea. The script itself took no longer than an hour to implement but downloading and processing what ended up being over 900 million games (1.9 TB) took the entire weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it was all finished I had a very satisifying table listing the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/owenps/Castlemates&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;top 25&lt;/a&gt; rated chess games ending in a checkmate by castling. I was extremely pleased with the results and thought other people may be interested in them as well. So I made &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;%28https://www.reddit.com/r/chess/comments/ojiy7p/top_25_rated_games_ending_in_a_checkmate_by%29&#34; &gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; on the subreddit r/chess and I checked almost an hour later to see 50 upvotes, then 100, then 300 later that evening, and it kept going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a crazy feeling getting a response like that. There were so many overwhelmingly positive comments from absolute strangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;do-it-for-the-right-reasons&#34;&gt;Do it for the right reasons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, despite all of this, if you are building a project yourself, the ignition should be your own curiosity. I say this knowing I&amp;rsquo;m not guilt free myself. In fact I often find myself starting projects just on the gamble of recieving recognition from others. However, I will say that my favourite projects have been the ones that I was genuinely curious about and wanted to explore for myself. That inner drive allowed me to put in double the hours and double the effort in creating an project I&amp;rsquo;m happy sharing to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sharing-your-project&#34;&gt;Sharing your project&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you do get a completed product and what to share it with people, search for communities of people who may be interested. These communities are often found on Reddit or on Discord. Search for relevant subreddits and servers and be thoughtful in how you present your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t start with an ask&lt;/strong&gt;. You should view your project as something you are giving. It&amp;rsquo;s primary goal should be to provide value, so worry about the ask later. People will be happy to give their feedback and support once they feel like it is deserved. If you do include an ask, frame it as an &amp;ldquo;if&amp;rdquo; statement: &amp;ldquo;if you enjoyed the project and wish to show your support then &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; this way it is optional and you respect those who aren&amp;rsquo;t currently willing to support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Present the project in an easily accessible format&lt;/strong&gt;. Speak in layman&amp;rsquo;s terms. Make sure the text is concise and digestable to a new reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be active in answering questions and responding to feedback&lt;/strong&gt;. It shows that you value the community&amp;rsquo;s opinion and feedback. Also, since everyone else can see your response, its important to craft your replies carefully. Being harsh to someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand or gives constructive critism will only damage you and your project&amp;rsquo;s reputation on that server/subreddit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may all seem very intuitive but each of these makes a huge difference in the eyes of a stranger who has no reason to care about your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To wrap things up, be proud of your work and take pride in it by showing it off to others. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think there is a small percentage of people who really enjoyed the project and its results and that makes me happy and is a huge part of why I love what I do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
